The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Fifty-Second Episode
The Royal Wedding
Before starting
today's episode,
let's briefly summarize
the previous episodes.
Grand Duke Duralumin, having become
an agent of the powerful Union X,
pushes his petty ambition..
..to the point of trying to kill
the King, the Queen, and Sapphire.
But the schemer
will not succeed in his intent.
He will die a sudden death,
due to the betrayal of
his assistant, Baron Nylon,
who seizes the throne.
Nylon receives the
Union X army in the castle.
Meanwhile Sapphire is saying goodbye
to her parents,
locked in the room
of skeletons,
and with three spheres of gold,
silver and copper,
which are believed to have the power to
protect the kingdom of Silverland,
she flees from the castle
and runs towards Goldland,
to ask for help
from Prince Franz, but...
What power will
these three spheres have?
If you have any power,
magic spheres, help me now!
Poor Sapphire...!
Father in heaven,
I will do anything for you,
But you, help Sapphire, please!
Damn it!
What is this sound of bells?
Enough! Enough!
Enough! Enough! Enough! Enough! Enough!
Enough! Enough! Enough!
You have truly gone mad, Nylon!
What is it? Speak!
I have come to tell you about the bells!
They are being rung by the people,
who are lamenting because
the King and Queen are dead.
What?!
Destroy all the bells!
And find Sapphire
as soon as possible!
Whether it be on a mountain,
valley, village... anywhere!
If it is necessary,
destroy the mountains!
Destroy all the places where it is
possible that Sapphire is hiding!
Our poor old city!
Union X has destroyed everything!
But you see that Sapphire
will defeat them!
Sapphire has lost
her father and mother,
but she has Prince Frank with her
Come, there is a surprise!
But first blindfold your eyes!
Check that everything is in order,
old owl!
And you, get ready, fireflies!
What you are about to see is a gift
for you from your forest friends!
Take off your blindfolds!
It’s truly delightful!
It’s magnificent!
Sapphire, do you like the gift
that we are giving you from the heart?
I like it very much!
You have been so kind!
I’m glad you like it!
But now, keep watching:
there is another gift for you.
Go!
Sapphire!
Forest friends,
I’m sorry if I wandered away.
Forgive me,
but I feel so weak!
I am trying to fight back,
but I always feel a great sadness!
I always feel like crying.
How much I would like to see
my father and my mother again..!
We understand you, Sapphire,
and we also suffer so much with you.
Heavenly Father,
I will do whatever you want,
but I beg you,
grant my wish!
I beg you, heavenly Father!
Give Sapphire back
her father and her mother!
Bring them back to life for her!
Grant my wish!
Please! I won't ask you
for anything else, I promise!
It's you, Heavenly Father!
Tink, once you were an angel,
but your wishes cannot
be easily granted.
If you wish to help
those you love,
you will have to sacrifice yourself to help them.
I will see how many sacrifices
you will have faced for them...
and I will decide whether to grant
your wish.
I will work for Sapphire!
I will do anything for her!
Oh, so much good stuff! Thank you!
I'm sure Sapphire will
be very happy about it!
What?!
And what are these?
Who brought them?
Are you telling me that you
found them, little mouse?
I'm sorry,
but they aren't edible.
I've got it! They could serve
as a clapper for our bells!
That way I'll wake up Sapphire!
Oh, Opal!
I understand, these three spheres
are very precious to Sapphire.
But couldn't you leave
them with me for a while?
I'll ring the bells
and wake up Sapphire!
I'll be careful not to
break them, don't worry!
What do you say, Opal?
Thank you!
Ready? Now let's hear how they sound!
The bells are ringing by themselves!
Did you hang the spheres
inside the bells?
Is it true that those three spheres
have great magical power?
Yes! Those three spheres
will protect Silverland,
the Royal Family and the people!
- These are the bells!
- What? - Listen!
The bells! The bells!
What is this sound?
I told you
to destroy all the bells!
Your order
has been carried out, master!
This sound...
My head hurts!
It's deafening me! Go and destroy
these ringing bells!
Look! The broken bells
are moving!
Help!
My arms
feel like fighting!
I also feel
full of energy again!
Sapphire, let's fight!
Let's drive X away! Let's all fight!
Yes, let's fight!
The bells are performing
the miracle!
The magic bells are for us!
Let's attack the army
of Union X!
- Yes, let's fight!
- Forward!
Let's go, Opal!
Bell, ring louder!
How stupid they are! They
will never defeat us! Advance!
Forward, destroy them!
Hurrah! Hooray! Victory! Hurrah!
Damn it!
It serves you right!
- Tink!
- Sapphire, the spheres are safe!
Help! Let's take shelter!
Damn it!
We've locked ourselves in here!
It's over for us!
Don't worry! I know
the way out of this cave.
We will come out near the castle.
But this is a stroke of luck!
I could get into the castle...
...and try to kill X!
Please, look for a weapon!
All we need is a weapon, that
way we can retake the castle!
I've got it: let's build it
with the three spheres!
Right! Right! We are the
best blacksmiths in the world!
Yes, it's true! It seems
like a good idea to me!
Tink is the one who has the three
spheres. But where is he? Tink! Tink!
- Tink! Tink!
- Tink, where are you? Tink!
Tink!
What hard work!
Goodness, they are so hard!
Tink! We were
looking for you! Let's go!
Tink!
I was just trying to build a
weapon with these three spheres.
Thank you for the thought, Tink.
Now we will show you what
great blacksmiths we are.
You'll see!
How marvelous!
- It looks like a magic weapon!
- Here you go, Tink!
- What is it? A trumpet?!
- That trumpet must have...
...the same power as the bells!
We made it with
the leftover gold!
- Wait here, please!
- Sapphire!
Stand back! I'll
take care of them!
Wait, Franz!
Sapphire!
A knight is approaching!
It's Sapphire!
Fire!
Sapphire!
Watch out!
- Thank you, Franz!
- Throw the magic axe, Sapphire!
It's the magic power of the spheres!
Now is the time to attack
the army of Union X!
Here we go! Go, Sapphire!
Cursed Sapphire!
- Sapphire! - Now I can avenge
my parents!
Sapphire!
Father in heaven, don't let Sapphire die!
Please, help her!
X is dead, Sapphire!
Watch out!
Tink!
Long live the great X!
Tink! Tink!
Tink! Tink..! Don't die!
Please, don't die!
Sapphire, it's time to say goodbye.
The Father in heaven is calling me,
so now I must go.
I won't let you go!
You will stay with me!
Father in heaven, I have done
everything to help Sapphire.
Will you grant
my wish now?
Alright, Tink.
I will grant your wish.
I will send Sapphire's father and mother
to Earth.
...and I will send them in your place,
while you will return to heaven,
beside me.
Heavenly Father, thank you.
Mom! Dad!
- Sapphire!
- My daughter!
Mom! Dad!
I am an angel once again.
On Earth, since then,
many years have passed.
I imagine that you, now,
will want to know what became...
...of the kingdom of Silverland,
of Sapphire and Franz, isn't that right?
Let's see! Silverland has
regained its former beauty...
...and everyone leads a happy life.
So, Sapphire,
are you ready to go out?
Yes!
I'm more than ready!
I see that Sapphire and
Franz will marry soon.
I'm sure they will be
a beautiful couple!
They will live happily all their lives!
I will ask the Heavenly
Father to be able to attend...
...their wedding.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP